{
	"description": "Common Japanese expressions",
	"type": "text",
	"timeout": 20,
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "to be on one's mind; to worry one; to care about; to be bothered by; to feel uneasy; to be anxious; to be curious about\nto feel like; to feel inclined to\nto fancy; to like; to catch one's eye\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気になる", "きになる" ], "comment": "Rank #1 (14247 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to mind (negative nuance); to care about; to worry; to pay undue (amount of) attention to (something)\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気にする", "きにする" ], "comment": "Rank #2 (7642 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold (in one's hand); to take (into one's hand)\nto own; to obtain\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手にする", "てにする" ], "comment": "Rank #3 (7635 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to taste; to eat\nto speak of; to refer to\n\nHint: 口に・・・", "answers": [ "口にする", "くちにする" ], "comment": "Rank #4 (7589 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to open one's mouth (to talk)\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を開く", "くちをひらく" ], "comment": "Rank #5 (6946 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bow; to bow one's head\nto apologize; to apologise\nto bow to; to yield to; to admire\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭を下げる", "あたまをさげる" ], "comment": "Rank #6 (6912 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to raise one's voice\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を上げる", "こえをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #7 (5162 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to experience\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を見る", "めをみる" ], "comment": "Rank #8 (4781 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be pleased with; to suit\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気に入る", "きにいる" ], "comment": "Rank #9 (4602 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shrug one's shoulders\n\nHint: 肩を・・・", "answers": [ "肩をすくめる", "かたをすくめる" ], "comment": "Rank #10 (4135 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to obtain; to procure\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に入れる", "てにいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #11 (4105 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to act as an intermediary\n\nHint: 中に・・・", "answers": [ "中に入る", "なかにはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #12 (3966 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take a breath; to take a short rest\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を吐く", "いきをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #13 (3734 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn up; to make an appearance; to put in an appearance\n\nHint: 顔を・・・", "answers": [ "顔を出す", "かおをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #14 (3597 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to incline one's head to the side (in doubt); to tilt one's head to the side (in confusion); to be puzzled\n\nHint: 首を・・・", "answers": [ "首を傾げる", "くびをかしげる" ], "comment": "Rank #15 (3157 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be helpful; to be useful\n\nHint: 役に・・・", "answers": [ "役に立つ", "やくにたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #16 (2849 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pretend not to see; to turn one's back on\n\nHint: 背を・・・", "answers": [ "背を向ける", "せをむける" ], "comment": "Rank #17 (2594 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hear; to hear by chance; to hear by accident; to catch (the sound)\n\nHint: 耳に・・・", "answers": [ "耳にする", "みみにする" ], "comment": "Rank #18 (2463 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "just right; ideal; perfectly suitable\nfetch!; bring me ...\n\nHint: 持っ・・・", "answers": [ "持って来い", "もってこい" ], "comment": "Rank #19 (2425 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn one's hand to; to reach out one's hand\nto get involved in; to make a move on\nto start a fight; to make a move in violence\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を出す", "てをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #20 (2381 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shift one's attention to; to shift one's focus on\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を向ける", "めをむける" ], "comment": "Rank #21 (2378 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to disappear\n\nHint: 姿を・・・", "answers": [ "姿を消す", "すがたをけす" ], "comment": "Rank #22 (2375 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shake one's head\n\nHint: 首を・・・", "answers": [ "首を横に振る", "くびをよこにふる" ], "comment": "Rank #23 (2364 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to receive favor (favour); to be much obliged to someone; to be indebted\n\nHint: 世話に・・・", "answers": [ "世話になる", "せわになる" ], "comment": "Rank #24 (2276 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to see; to witness; to observe; to catch sight of; to get a glimpse of; to encounter\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目にする", "めにする" ], "comment": "Rank #25 (2097 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to dream; to have a dream\n\nHint: 夢を・・・", "answers": [ "夢を見る", "ゆめをみる" ], "comment": "Rank #26 (2044 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stare in wonder; to be amazed\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を丸くする", "めをまるくする" ], "comment": "Rank #27 (2026 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have an interest (in something); to feel inclined (toward doing something)\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気がある", "きがある" ], "comment": "Rank #28 (2014 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to wake up\nto sober up; to come to one's senses; to become enlightened\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を覚ます", "めをさます" ], "comment": "Rank #29 (1993 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put into words; to express\n\nHint: 口に・・・", "answers": [ "口に出す", "くちにだす" ], "comment": "Rank #30 (1945 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lie down (and rest)\n\nHint: 横に・・・", "answers": [ "横になる", "よこになる" ], "comment": "Rank #31 (1893 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to catch one's breath; to gulp; to have one's breath taken away; to gasp\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を呑む", "いきをのむ" ], "comment": "Rank #32 (1876 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to withdraw from (a deal); to wash one's hands of\nto lead by the hand\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を引く", "てをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #33 (1838 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fold one's arms\nto link arms with someone\n\nHint: 腕を・・・", "answers": [ "腕を組む", "うでをくむ" ], "comment": "Rank #34 (1770 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to catch sight of; to come into view; to happen to see\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に入る", "めにはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #35 (1694 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to come to one's senses\nto calm down\n\nHint: 我に・・・", "answers": [ "我に返る", "われにかえる" ], "comment": "Rank #36 (1664 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be visible\nclear; distinct; apparent\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に見える", "めにみえる" ], "comment": "Rank #37 (1514 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hear of\n\nHint: 耳に・・・", "answers": [ "耳に入る", "みみにはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #38 (1491 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose consciousness; to faint; to black out\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を失う", "きをうしなう" ], "comment": "Rank #39 (1490 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get up (e.g. from bed)\nto make one's way in the world; to achieve in life\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を起こす", "みをおこす" ], "comment": "Rank #40 (1475 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take measures (in face of events being anticipated)\nto come to an agreement (in bargaining, etc.); to strike a bargain\nto clap one's hands together\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を打つ", "てをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #41 (1471 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to coo at; to behave like a spoiled child\nto snort; to sniff\n\nHint: 鼻を・・・", "answers": [ "鼻を鳴らす", "はなをならす" ], "comment": "Rank #42 (1452 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get angry; to take offense; to take offence; to be furious\n\nHint: 腹が・・・", "answers": [ "腹が立つ", "はらがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #43 (1431 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to notice; to become aware; to perceive; to realize; to realise\nto be scrupulous; to be attentive\nto recover consciousness; to come to oneself\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が付く", "きがつく" ], "comment": "Rank #44 (1420 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be noticeable; to notice; to catch one's eye\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目につく", "めにつく" ], "comment": "Rank #45 (1371 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cast down one's eyes\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を伏せる", "めをふせる" ], "comment": "Rank #46 (1364 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to set foot into; to enter; to step inside; to cross the threshold\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足を踏み入れる", "あしをふみいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #47 (1355 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to raise one's hand or hands\nto surrender\nto raise a hand to someone (as a threat to strike)\nto improve\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を上げる", "てをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #48 (1354 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to meet; to face someone\n\nHint: 顔を・・・", "answers": [ "顔を合わせる", "かおをあわせる" ], "comment": "Rank #49 (1339 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take offense; to take offence; to get angry; to lose one's temper\n\nHint: 腹を・・・", "answers": [ "腹を立てる", "はらをたてる" ], "comment": "Rank #50 (1309 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to awaken; to perk up; to snap out (of something)\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が覚める", "めがさめる" ], "comment": "Rank #51 (1271 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to throw out one's chest; to be puffed up with pride\n\nHint: 胸を・・・", "answers": [ "胸を張る", "むねをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #52 (1245 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pause; to have a short intermission\n\nHint: 間を・・・", "answers": [ "間を置く", "まをおく" ], "comment": "Rank #53 (1218 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shut one's eyes\nto ignore; to pretend not to know\nto die\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目をつぶる", "めをつぶる" ], "comment": "Rank #54 (1193 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be greatly perplexed; to be troubled; to be at wits' end\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭を抱える", "あたまをかかえる" ], "comment": "Rank #55 (1188 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make sure of; to call attention to; to emphasize; to emphasise\n\nHint: 念を・・・", "answers": [ "念を押す", "ねんをおす" ], "comment": "Rank #56 (1187 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make fun of; to look down on; to make light of\n\nHint: 馬鹿に・・・", "answers": [ "馬鹿にする", "ばかにする" ], "comment": "Rank #57 (1175 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cut into (a conversation); to interject\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を挟む", "くちをはさむ" ], "comment": "Rank #58 (1134 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shake one's head (in denial)\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭を振る", "かぶりをふる" ], "comment": "Rank #59 (1126 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to place both hands on the ground (to express respect, apology or to present a request)\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を突く", "てをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #60 (1122 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lend an ear; to hearken; to give an ear to; to listen carefully\n\nHint: 耳を・・・", "answers": [ "耳を傾ける", "みみをかたむける" ], "comment": "Rank #61 (1072 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take someone's hand\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を取る", "てをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #62 (1038 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to come together; to join\n\nHint: 一緒に・・・", "answers": [ "一緒になる", "いっしょになる" ], "comment": "Rank #63 (1033 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to listen carefully; to strain one's ears\n\nHint: 耳を・・・", "answers": [ "耳を澄ます", "みみをすます" ], "comment": "Rank #64 (1026 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lead; to take the initiative\nto take precedence (e.g. sadness taking precedence over anger)\nto be most essential\n\nHint: 先に・・・", "answers": [ "先に立つ", "さきにたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #65 (1021 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to perspire; to sweat\n\nHint: 汗を・・・", "answers": [ "汗をかく", "あせをかく" ], "comment": "Rank #66 (1009 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look away; to avert one's eyes\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を逸らす", "めをそらす" ], "comment": "Rank #67 (1003 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go; to come; to turn out (at a meeting, event, etc.); to show up; to make your way to\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足を運ぶ", "あしをはこぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #68 (992 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to interrupt a conversation\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を出す", "くちをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #69 (988 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unacceptable; no good; complete failure; inadequate\n\nHint: なっ・・・", "answers": [ "なっていない", "なっていない" ], "comment": "Rank #70 (988 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to prove successful; to come to good; to take hold\n\nHint: 物に・・・", "answers": [ "物になる", "ものになる" ], "comment": "Rank #71 (987 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to greet; to call out to someone\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を掛ける", "こえをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #72 (978 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shed light; to cast light\n\nHint: 光を・・・", "answers": [ "光を放つ", "ひかりをはなつ" ], "comment": "Rank #73 (962 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn on one's heel; to turn back; to return\n\nHint: 踵を・・・", "answers": [ "踵を返す", "くびすをかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #74 (961 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn on one's heel; to turn back; to return\n\nHint: 踵を・・・", "answers": [ "踵を返す", "きびすをかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #75 (961 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "It's no joke\nGimme a break!; Sod that!\n\nHint: 冗談・・・", "answers": [ "冗談じゃない", "じょうだんじゃない" ], "comment": "Rank #76 (944 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "natural; understandable\n\nHint: 無理も・・・", "answers": [ "無理もない", "むりもない" ], "comment": "Rank #77 (928 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to correct; to touch up; to smarten up\nto put one's hand in (e.g. pocket)\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を入れる", "てをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #78 (899 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to come to mind; to pop into one's head\n\nHint: 頭に・・・", "answers": [ "頭に浮かぶ", "あたまにうかぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #79 (870 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "droop one's shoulders (in disappointment); to drop one's shoulders\n\nHint: 肩を・・・", "answers": [ "肩を落とす", "かたをおとす" ], "comment": "Rank #80 (868 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to strain one's eyes; to look closely; to stare at\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を凝らす", "めをこらす" ], "comment": "Rank #81 (851 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "at disadvantage; having no edge; having poor prospects\n\nHint: 分が・・・", "answers": [ "分が悪い", "ぶがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #82 (848 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lend a hand; to help\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を貸す", "てをかす" ], "comment": "Rank #83 (848 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to half-rise to one's feet\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を浮かす", "こしをうかす" ], "comment": "Rank #84 (845 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to act as an intermediary; to step in; to come between; to intervene; to interject\n\nHint: 間に・・・", "answers": [ "間に入る", "あいだにはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #85 (841 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a fist; to clench one's fist\n\nHint: 拳を・・・", "answers": [ "拳を握る", "こぶしをにぎる" ], "comment": "Rank #86 (841 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take one's eyes off\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を離す", "めをはなす" ], "comment": "Rank #87 (831 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be helpful; to be dependable\n\nHint: 力に・・・", "answers": [ "力になる", "ちからになる" ], "comment": "Rank #88 (823 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have an eye on; to zero in on\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目をつける", "めをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #89 (801 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to float in the air\nto be unfinished; to be unsettled; to be undecided\n\nHint: 宙に・・・", "answers": [ "宙に浮く", "ちゅうにうく" ], "comment": "Rank #90 (794 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be wide-eyed (in surprise); to open one's eyes wide (in wonder); to be amazed (at, by)\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を見張る", "めをみはる" ], "comment": "Rank #91 (773 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to scan; to look over\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を通す", "めをとおす" ], "comment": "Rank #92 (763 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to live under another's roof; to become a dependent on\nto flatten oneself (against); to lean in close to\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を寄せる", "みをよせる" ], "comment": "Rank #93 (760 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to raise one's voice; to shout\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を張り上げる", "こえをはりあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #94 (753 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be careful; to pay attention; to take care\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を付ける", "きをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #95 (743 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(Stand to) attention!\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を付け", "きをつけ" ], "comment": "Rank #96 (743 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn one's back on\nto be uninterested in\n\nHint: 背中を・・・", "answers": [ "背中を向ける", "せなかをむける" ], "comment": "Rank #97 (742 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put effort into; to strain; to put strength into; to put forth effort\n\nHint: 力を・・・", "answers": [ "力を入れる", "ちからをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #98 (712 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn one's back to\n\nHint: 背に・・・", "answers": [ "背にする", "せにする" ], "comment": "Rank #99 (697 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to join hands together\nto join forces; to collaborate\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を組む", "てをくむ" ], "comment": "Rank #100 (676 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to open one's eyes wide (in anger, surprise, etc.); to goggle at\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を剥く", "めをむく" ], "comment": "Rank #101 (652 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get up (from sitting)\nto finally start to do something; to get off one's arse (ass)\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を上げる", "こしをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #102 (648 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to force one's way through\n\nHint: 割っ・・・", "answers": [ "割って入る", "わってはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #103 (647 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to exchange words\n\nHint: 言葉を・・・", "answers": [ "言葉を交わす", "ことばをかわす" ], "comment": "Rank #104 (641 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bear up in tragedy; to stand pain well; to hold one's temper\nto clench one's teeth; to grit one's teeth\n\nHint: 歯を・・・", "answers": [ "歯を食いしばる", "はをくいしばる" ], "comment": "Rank #105 (629 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become blue; to turn green\nto turn pale; to blanch (with fear)\n\nHint: 青く・・・", "answers": [ "青くなる", "あおくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #106 (609 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cock one's head in puzzlement; to tilt one's head in contemplation; to wrack one's brain; to think hard\n\nHint: 首を・・・", "answers": [ "首を捻る", "くびをひねる" ], "comment": "Rank #107 (608 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "no matter what it takes; by any means necessary; at all costs; by hook or by crook\n\nHint: 何と・・・", "answers": [ "何としても", "なんとしても" ], "comment": "Rank #108 (599 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to care for someone; to look after someone\n\nHint: 面倒を・・・", "answers": [ "面倒を見る", "めんどうをみる" ], "comment": "Rank #109 (590 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make use of aizuchi; to back-channel; to throw in interjections to show that one is paying attention\n\nHint: 相槌を・・・", "answers": [ "相槌を打つ", "あいづちをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #110 (589 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to completely rethink; to pull one's self together\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を取り直す", "きをとりなおす" ], "comment": "Rank #111 (585 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do one good; to be beneficial; to be good for the body; to be helpful\n\nHint: 身に・・・", "answers": [ "身になる", "みになる" ], "comment": "Rank #112 (584 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put out one's tongue; to stick out one's tongue\n\nHint: 舌を・・・", "answers": [ "舌を出す", "したをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #113 (576 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be at a loss; to be puzzled\n\nHint: 途方に・・・", "answers": [ "途方に暮れる", "とほうにくれる" ], "comment": "Rank #114 (572 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to laugh scornfully\n\nHint: 鼻で・・・", "answers": [ "鼻で笑う", "はなでわらう" ], "comment": "Rank #115 (554 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become good-looking; to start looking appropriate (for something)\n\nHint: 様に・・・", "answers": [ "様になる", "さまになる" ], "comment": "Rank #116 (532 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get; to secure; to take possession of; to make one's own; to win (someone's heart)\nto learn; to master\nto complete\n\nHint: 物に・・・", "answers": [ "物にする", "ものにする" ], "comment": "Rank #117 (530 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look away; to turn away\n\nHint: 横を・・・", "answers": [ "横を向く", "よこをむく" ], "comment": "Rank #118 (521 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to open the lid; to lift a lid\nto open the lid (on); to make public\nto start (something)\nto look at the results (consequences, outcome, effect); to look at the condition of something\nto open (of a theatre)\n\nHint: 蓋を・・・", "answers": [ "蓋を開ける", "ふたをあける" ], "comment": "Rank #119 (515 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be elated; to be excited; to be caught up in the moment; to be carried away; to get cocky\nto get up to speed; to move into gear\n\nHint: 調子に・・・", "answers": [ "調子に乗る", "ちょうしにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #120 (501 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to speak; to utter\nto mediate\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を利く", "くちをきく" ], "comment": "Rank #121 (496 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fire from a job; to dismiss; to discharge\nto behead\n\nHint: 首を・・・", "answers": [ "首を切る", "くびをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #122 (468 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose one's life\n\nHint: 命を・・・", "answers": [ "命を落とす", "いのちをおとす" ], "comment": "Rank #123 (463 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be satisfied; to feel good\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が済む", "きがすむ" ], "comment": "Rank #124 (463 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be taken aback; to be astonished; to be dumbfounded\n\nHint: 呆気に・・・", "answers": [ "呆気にとられる", "あっけにとられる" ], "comment": "Rank #125 (463 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to picture; to come into one's mind; to remember\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に浮かぶ", "めにうかぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #126 (456 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to assist; to help out\n\nHint: 力を・・・", "answers": [ "力を貸す", "ちからをかす" ], "comment": "Rank #127 (451 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to keep a watchful eye on\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を光らす", "めをひからす" ], "comment": "Rank #128 (451 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to leave a trail; to leave traces; to have a lasting effect\n\nHint: 尾を・・・", "answers": [ "尾を引く", "おをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #129 (439 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pay attention; to be watchful\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を配る", "きをくばる" ], "comment": "Rank #130 (437 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bare one's fangs; to snarl at\n\nHint: 牙を・・・", "answers": [ "牙を剥く", "きばをむく" ], "comment": "Rank #131 (435 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do oneself; to do by oneself\nto start work (on); to commence\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を下す", "てをくだす" ], "comment": "Rank #132 (435 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold one's breath; to catch one's breath\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を殺す", "いきをころす" ], "comment": "Rank #133 (434 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose focus; to let one's mind wander; to relax one's attention\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を抜く", "きをぬく" ], "comment": "Rank #134 (431 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make the necessary preparations in secret\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を回す", "てをまわす" ], "comment": "Rank #135 (429 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to breathe heavily (e.g. with much movement of the shoulders)\n\nHint: 肩で・・・", "answers": [ "肩で息をする", "かたでいきをする" ], "comment": "Rank #136 (428 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "a matter of time; matter of hours; question of time\n\nHint: 時間の・・・", "answers": [ "時間の問題", "じかんのもんだい" ], "comment": "Rank #137 (428 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be embarrassed; to lose face\n\nHint: 恥を・・・", "answers": [ "恥をかく", "はじをかく" ], "comment": "Rank #138 (425 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to let out a cry; to shout\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を立てる", "こえをたてる" ], "comment": "Rank #139 (424 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to devote oneself; to do one thing exclusively; to make a job of\nto decide to\n\nHint: 事と・・・", "answers": [ "事とする", "こととする" ], "comment": "Rank #140 (418 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to keep one's mouth shut; to refuse to talk\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を閉ざす", "くちをとざす" ], "comment": "Rank #141 (414 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "profitable; lucrative\n\nHint: 金に・・・", "answers": [ "金になる", "かねになる" ], "comment": "Rank #142 (414 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "having a headache\nracking one's brains; troubling over something\n\nHint: 頭が・・・", "answers": [ "頭が痛い", "あたまがいたい" ], "comment": "Rank #143 (411 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "depressed; bummed out; down; heavy-hearted; heavy-spirited; feeling reluctant (to do)\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が重い", "きがおもい" ], "comment": "Rank #144 (399 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to work hard; to sweat\nto wash off one's sweat\n\nHint: 汗を・・・", "answers": [ "汗を流す", "あせをながす" ], "comment": "Rank #145 (393 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "quickly, suddenly (while one is watching); before one's eyes\n\nHint: 見る・・・", "answers": [ "見る間に", "みるまに" ], "comment": "Rank #146 (392 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to throw oneself (e.g. off a cliff, etc.)\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を投げる", "みをなげる" ], "comment": "Rank #147 (391 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bend one's head slightly to one side; to look slightly doubtful\n\nHint: 小首を・・・", "answers": [ "小首を傾げる", "こくびをかしげる" ], "comment": "Rank #148 (388 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pout\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を尖らせる", "くちをとがらせる" ], "comment": "Rank #149 (386 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to faint; to lose consciousness\nto feel overwhelmed; to be astounded\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が遠くなる", "きがとおくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #150 (384 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to blush\n\nHint: 頬を・・・", "answers": [ "頬を染める", "ほおをそめる" ], "comment": "Rank #151 (378 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to experience chest pain; to have a pain in one's chest\nto feel sick at heart; to have one's heart ache; to be anguished\n\nHint: 胸が・・・", "answers": [ "胸が痛む", "むねがいたむ" ], "comment": "Rank #152 (372 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go flying along; to move fast (against the wind)\n\nHint: 風を・・・", "answers": [ "風を切る", "かぜをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #153 (369 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not worth considering; out of the question\n\nHint: 話に・・・", "answers": [ "話にならない", "はなしにならない" ], "comment": "Rank #154 (365 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to require much effort; to be hard to do\n\nHint: 骨が・・・", "answers": [ "骨が折れる", "ほねがおれる" ], "comment": "Rank #155 (359 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be evasive; to not commit oneself\n\nHint: 言葉を・・・", "answers": [ "言葉を濁す", "ことばをにごす" ], "comment": "Rank #156 (353 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "presenting no difficulty; not hard\n\nHint: 物な・・・", "answers": [ "物ならず", "ものならず" ], "comment": "Rank #157 (353 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to attract someone's affection\nto sound out somebody\nto get one's hooks into\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を引く", "きをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #158 (352 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have one's attention attracted (caught); to be preoccupied with\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を取られる", "きをとられる" ], "comment": "Rank #159 (348 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "It's no use\n\nHint: 始ま・・・", "answers": [ "始まらない", "はじまらない" ], "comment": "Rank #160 (347 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stand, walk, etc. shoulder-to-shoulder\nto be on a par with\n\nHint: 肩を・・・", "answers": [ "肩を並べる", "かたをならべる" ], "comment": "Rank #161 (339 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to attract notice; to catch the eye; to stand out\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を引く", "めをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #162 (337 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be able to reach; to be within one's reach; to be able to afford; to have the means to buy\nto be near (a certain age)\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が届く", "てがとどく" ], "comment": "Rank #163 (336 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "serves you right!; see what happens!\n\nHint: 様を・・・", "answers": [ "様を見ろ", "ざまをみろ" ], "comment": "Rank #164 (334 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be descended from; to inherit (a disposition, etc.) from one's ancestors\n\nHint: 血を・・・", "answers": [ "血を引く", "ちをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #165 (333 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to not believe one's ears\n\nHint: 耳を・・・", "answers": [ "耳を疑う", "みみをうたがう" ], "comment": "Rank #166 (329 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make efforts; to take pains\nto break one's bone\n\nHint: 骨を・・・", "answers": [ "骨を折る", "ほねをおる" ], "comment": "Rank #167 (326 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to dislocate one's back\nto be unable to stand up due to fear or surprise\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を抜かす", "こしをぬかす" ], "comment": "Rank #168 (323 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be excited about; to get all worked up about\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が立つ", "きがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #169 (323 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to mediate; to intervene\n\nHint: 間に・・・", "answers": [ "間に立つ", "あいだにたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #170 (319 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold one's breath\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を詰める", "いきをつめる" ], "comment": "Rank #171 (318 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "nonchalant air; unruffled air\n\nHint: 涼し・・・", "answers": [ "涼しい顔", "すずしいかお" ], "comment": "Rank #172 (313 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pay attention to another's needs; to attend to; to fuss about; to take into consideration\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を使う", "きをつかう" ], "comment": "Rank #173 (311 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to reply; to respond; to answer\n\nHint: 言葉を・・・", "answers": [ "言葉を返す", "ことばをかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #174 (308 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to accept help; to get help; to ask for help\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を借りる", "てをかりる" ], "comment": "Rank #175 (306 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold one's tongue; to shut up\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を噤む", "くちをつぐむ" ], "comment": "Rank #176 (306 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to doubt one's own eyes\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を疑う", "めをうたがう" ], "comment": "Rank #177 (305 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to solve a mystery\n\nHint: 謎を・・・", "answers": [ "謎を解く", "なぞをとく" ], "comment": "Rank #178 (299 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to outwit; to outsmart; to counterplot; to defeat\nto pierce something all the way through\n\nHint: 裏を・・・", "answers": [ "裏をかく", "うらをかく" ], "comment": "Rank #179 (299 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "cannot understand; doesn't make sense; unconvincing; hard to swallow; doesn't ring true\n\nHint: 腑に・・・", "answers": [ "腑に落ちない", "ふにおちない" ], "comment": "Rank #180 (292 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "beyond imagination; unimaginable\n\nHint: 想像を・・・", "answers": [ "想像を絶する", "そうぞうをぜっする" ], "comment": "Rank #181 (292 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "after all is said and done; to say the least\n\nHint: 何と・・・", "answers": [ "何と言っても", "なんといっても" ], "comment": "Rank #182 (290 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "reluctant to; not inclined to; disinclined; unwilling\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が進まない", "きがすすまない" ], "comment": "Rank #183 (289 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give off sparks; to spark; to scintillate\nto have a heated argument; to combat; to do something fiercely\n\nHint: 火花を・・・", "answers": [ "火花を散らす", "ひばなをちらす" ], "comment": "Rank #184 (289 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to meet face-to-face\n\nHint: 面と・・・", "answers": [ "面と向かう", "めんとむかう" ], "comment": "Rank #185 (288 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pant; to gasp; to be short of breath; to be excited\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を弾ませる", "いきをはずませる" ], "comment": "Rank #186 (287 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to forget oneself; to lose control of oneself\n\nHint: 我を・・・", "answers": [ "我を忘れる", "われをわすれる" ], "comment": "Rank #187 (282 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to dart one's eyes about; to be surprised; to be bewildered; to be confused; to be flustered\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を白黒させる", "めをしろくろさせる" ], "comment": "Rank #188 (281 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get goosebumps\n\nHint: 鳥肌が・・・", "answers": [ "鳥肌が立つ", "とりはだがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #189 (281 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take seriously; to believe\n\nHint: 真に・・・", "answers": [ "真に受ける", "まにうける" ], "comment": "Rank #190 (280 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pay attention to; to make sure; to double check\n\nHint: 念を・・・", "answers": [ "念を入れる", "ねんをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #191 (278 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to choke; to have trouble breathing\n\nHint: 息が・・・", "answers": [ "息が詰まる", "いきがつまる" ], "comment": "Rank #192 (278 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "usual; mediocre; monotonous\n\nHint: 変哲も・・・", "answers": [ "変哲もない", "へんてつもない" ], "comment": "Rank #193 (276 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to settle down; to get a steady job; to marry and raise a family\nto attire oneself; to outfit oneself\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を固める", "みをかためる" ], "comment": "Rank #194 (276 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to ease up (on an opponent); to cut corners; to be shoddy\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を抜く", "てをぬく" ], "comment": "Rank #195 (273 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give advice; to counsel; to take part in a consultation\n\nHint: 相談に・・・", "answers": [ "相談に乗る", "そうだんにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #196 (271 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be astonished\n\nHint: 舌を・・・", "answers": [ "舌を巻く", "したをまく" ], "comment": "Rank #197 (271 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to grow old; to age\n\nHint: 年を・・・", "answers": [ "年を取る", "としをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #198 (270 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be thirsty\n\nHint: 喉が・・・", "answers": [ "喉が渇く", "のどがかわく" ], "comment": "Rank #199 (268 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to knit one's brows (in discomfort, unease, disapproval, etc.); to raise one's eyebrows; to frown; to scowl\n\nHint: 眉を・・・", "answers": [ "眉を顰める", "まゆをひそめる" ], "comment": "Rank #200 (268 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become an expert; to be master at\n\nHint: 堂に・・・", "answers": [ "堂に入る", "どうにいる" ], "comment": "Rank #201 (265 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to flare up at\n\nHint: 食っ・・・", "answers": [ "食ってかかる", "くってかかる" ], "comment": "Rank #202 (264 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel awkward; to feel ashamed; to feel inferior; to feel shy (about doing something)\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が引ける", "きがひける" ], "comment": "Rank #203 (263 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel exhausted (after having been stressed); to feel spent; to feel relieved (from stress)\nto become stale (i.e. of a carbonated beverage); to go flat; to lose flavor; to lose flavour\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が抜ける", "きがぬける" ], "comment": "Rank #204 (263 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn over (in one's sleep); to toss and turn (in bed)\nto change sides; to double-cross; to betray\n\nHint: 寝返りを・・・", "answers": [ "寝返りを打つ", "ねがえりをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #205 (262 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get along (with someone)\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が合う", "きがあう" ], "comment": "Rank #206 (260 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "knowing only too well; being fully aware of\n\nHint: 百も・・・", "answers": [ "百も承知", "ひゃくもしょうち" ], "comment": "Rank #207 (260 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to poke one's nose into another's affairs; to have a hand in; to take a (deep) interest in; to meddle in\nto poke one's head (into a room)\n\nHint: 首を・・・", "answers": [ "首を突っ込む", "くびをつっこむ" ], "comment": "Rank #208 (257 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to resolve to do; to make up one's mind to do; to set one's heart on; to have one's heart set on\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を決める", "こころをきめる" ], "comment": "Rank #209 (255 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to roll around laughing; to fold up; to hold one's sides with laughter\n\nHint: 腹を・・・", "answers": [ "腹を抱える", "はらをかかえる" ], "comment": "Rank #210 (252 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cut off (a relationship)\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を切る", "てをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #211 (251 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lend an ear to; to listen to\n\nHint: 耳を・・・", "answers": [ "耳を貸す", "みみをかす" ], "comment": "Rank #212 (250 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cross the ocean (i.e. to go to or come from overseas)\n\nHint: 海を・・・", "answers": [ "海を渡る", "うみをわたる" ], "comment": "Rank #213 (250 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give oneself to (esp. of a woman to a man); to surrender oneself to\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を任せる", "みをまかせる" ], "comment": "Rank #214 (248 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unusually; uncharacteristically\n\nHint: 常な・・・", "answers": [ "常ならず", "つねならず" ], "comment": "Rank #215 (248 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn pale; to lose color; to lose colour\n\nHint: 色を・・・", "answers": [ "色を失う", "いろをうしなう" ], "comment": "Rank #216 (248 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unable to stomach; sticking in one's throat; displeased with\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気に食わない", "きにくわない" ], "comment": "Rank #217 (247 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to worry; to fret (over something); to be worried; to be anxious\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気に病む", "きにやむ" ], "comment": "Rank #218 (246 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to confess; to speak out; to disclose; to tell\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を割る", "くちをわる" ], "comment": "Rank #219 (241 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in front of one's eyes; just nearby; within a stone's throw\n\nHint: 目と・・・", "answers": [ "目と鼻の先", "めとはなのさき" ], "comment": "Rank #220 (240 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "anything and everything; from top to toe; from A to Z\n\nHint: 何から・・・", "answers": [ "何から何まで", "なにからなにまで" ], "comment": "Rank #221 (232 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to nod one's head; to nod yes; to agree\n\nHint: 首を・・・", "answers": [ "首を縦に振る", "くびをたてにふる" ], "comment": "Rank #222 (232 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the New Year begins; the New Year starts\n\nHint: 年が・・・", "answers": [ "年が明ける", "としがあける" ], "comment": "Rank #223 (230 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be relieved; to feel relieved\n\nHint: 胸を・・・", "answers": [ "胸を撫で下ろす", "むねをなでおろす" ], "comment": "Rank #224 (230 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pull (the puppet) strings; to direct things from behind the scenes\nto stretch out (and keep going); to linger on\n\nHint: 糸を・・・", "answers": [ "糸を引く", "いとをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #225 (228 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bother; to meddle; to poke one's nose (into another's business); to be too helpful\n\nHint: 世話を・・・", "answers": [ "世話を焼く", "せわをやく" ], "comment": "Rank #226 (227 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do something behind someone's back; to do something stealthily\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を盗む", "めをぬすむ" ], "comment": "Rank #227 (225 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to rack one's brains\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭を悩ます", "あたまをなやます" ], "comment": "Rank #228 (224 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take care of some business; to go on an errand\nto relieve oneself; to do one's business; to go to the toilet\n\nHint: 用を・・・", "answers": [ "用を足す", "ようをたす" ], "comment": "Rank #229 (224 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in a manner of speaking; as it were; so to speak; if you like; per se\n\nHint: 言っ・・・", "answers": [ "言ってみれば", "いってみれば" ], "comment": "Rank #230 (223 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to (relax and) stretch one's legs out\nto go for a further walk\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足を伸ばす", "あしをのばす" ], "comment": "Rank #231 (222 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel like; to feel inclined to do\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が向く", "きがむく" ], "comment": "Rank #232 (221 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "I don't know about ... but; it may be possible for ... but\n\nHint: いざ・・・", "answers": [ "いざ知らず", "いざしらず" ], "comment": "Rank #233 (219 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to work hard; to work diligently\n\nHint: 精を・・・", "answers": [ "精を出す", "せいをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #234 (219 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to quit (a shady business); to wash one's hands of; to cut one's ties with; to turn over a new leaf; to go straight\nto wash one's feet\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足を洗う", "あしをあらう" ], "comment": "Rank #235 (218 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cast a shadow (literal or figurative)\n\nHint: 影を・・・", "answers": [ "影を落とす", "かげをおとす" ], "comment": "Rank #236 (217 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be captivated (visually)\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を奪われる", "めをうばわれる" ], "comment": "Rank #237 (217 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unknown; obscure; insignificant\n\nHint: 名も・・・", "answers": [ "名もない", "なもない" ], "comment": "Rank #238 (217 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get mad; to be highly offended; to get pissed off; to get angry; to lose one's cool\n\nHint: 頭に・・・", "answers": [ "頭に来る", "あたまにくる" ], "comment": "Rank #239 (216 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "spoiled; unmanageable; uncontrollable; incorrigible; obstreperous\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に負えない", "てにおえない" ], "comment": "Rank #240 (215 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the very picture of ...\n\nHint: 絵に・・・", "answers": [ "絵に描いたよう", "えにかいたよう" ], "comment": "Rank #241 (214 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be reduced to ashes; to be cremated\n\nHint: 灰に・・・", "answers": [ "灰になる", "はいになる" ], "comment": "Rank #242 (212 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lay hands on; to touch\nto care for; to look after\nto make off with; to steal\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を掛ける", "てをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #243 (211 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to perform some process; to apply some treatment\nto revise; to correct\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を加える", "てをくわえる" ], "comment": "Rank #244 (211 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become famous\nto go out into the world; to make one's way in the world; to appear; to be published\n\nHint: 世に・・・", "answers": [ "世に出る", "よにでる" ], "comment": "Rank #245 (211 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to count on one's fingers\n\nHint: 指を・・・", "answers": [ "指を折る", "ゆびをおる" ], "comment": "Rank #246 (210 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "peremptorily; willy-nilly; forcibly\n\nHint: 有無を・・・", "answers": [ "有無を言わせず", "うむをいわせず" ], "comment": "Rank #247 (209 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take the form (of); to assume a shape\n\nHint: 形を・・・", "answers": [ "形を取る", "かたちをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #248 (208 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to impress; to move one's heart; to touch (a person's heart)\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を動かす", "こころをうごかす" ], "comment": "Rank #249 (207 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be congenial; to agree with one; to be in one's nature\n\nHint: 性に・・・", "answers": [ "性に合う", "しょうにあう" ], "comment": "Rank #250 (207 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pursue\nto die right after a loved one; to kill oneself (because one misses or longs to be with a loved one)\nto follow an example set by earlier generations (or one's master, etc.)\n\nHint: 跡を・・・", "answers": [ "跡を追う", "あとをおう" ], "comment": "Rank #251 (206 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "out of character; unlike one\n\nHint: 柄に・・・", "answers": [ "柄にもない", "がらにもない" ], "comment": "Rank #252 (206 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "strong-willed; strong of heart\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が強い", "きがつよい" ], "comment": "Rank #253 (204 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to run out of breath; to be short of breath; to lose one's breath\nto run out of steam; to be unable to continue; to collapse\nto die\n\nHint: 息が・・・", "answers": [ "息が切れる", "いきがきれる" ], "comment": "Rank #254 (204 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hurt one's feelings; to rub someone the wrong way\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気に障る", "きにさわる" ], "comment": "Rank #255 (204 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold one's breath (in fear, anxiety, etc.)\n\nHint: 固唾を・・・", "answers": [ "固唾を呑む", "かたずをのむ" ], "comment": "Rank #256 (203 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to forestall; to beat to the punch; to anticipate\nto play the first move (e.g. in go)\n\nHint: 先手を・・・", "answers": [ "先手を打つ", "せんてをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #257 (201 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cause a loss\nto make a hole (in)\n\nHint: 穴を・・・", "answers": [ "穴をあける", "あなをあける" ], "comment": "Rank #258 (201 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be ready to cry; to be on the point of tears\n\nHint: べそを・・・", "answers": [ "べそをかく", "べそをかく" ], "comment": "Rank #259 (200 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "luckily or unluckily; for good or for evil\n\nHint: 幸か・・・", "answers": [ "幸か不幸か", "こうかふこうか" ], "comment": "Rank #260 (199 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to muffle one's voice; to speak (or sob, etc.) quietly\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を殺す", "こえをころす" ], "comment": "Rank #261 (199 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get a divorce; to sever connections\n\nHint: 縁を・・・", "answers": [ "縁を切る", "えんをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #262 (198 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to accept an offer; to be charmed by someone's kind words and do as he wishes\n\nHint: 言葉に・・・", "answers": [ "言葉に甘える", "ことばにあまえる" ], "comment": "Rank #263 (196 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go through; to suffer; to experience (something unpleasant)\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に会う", "めにあう" ], "comment": "Rank #264 (193 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to catch the eye; to attract attention\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に触れる", "めにふれる" ], "comment": "Rank #265 (192 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to resume breathing; to come around; to come back to life\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を吹き返す", "いきをふきかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #266 (191 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "at any rate; anyhow; anyway; in any case; because\n\nHint: 何に・・・", "answers": [ "何にせよ", "なんにせよ" ], "comment": "Rank #267 (191 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to set fire to\n\nHint: 火を・・・", "answers": [ "火を放つ", "ひをはなつ" ], "comment": "Rank #268 (190 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get involved (with); to begin (with); to have a hand (in)\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を染める", "てをそめる" ], "comment": "Rank #269 (190 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be bewitched by a fox; to be confused\n\nHint: 狐に・・・", "answers": [ "狐につままれる", "きつねにつままれる" ], "comment": "Rank #270 (190 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to probe; to search; to sound out; to investigate\n\nHint: 探りを・・・", "answers": [ "探りを入れる", "さぐりをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #271 (190 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to succeed; to bear fruit\n\nHint: 功を・・・", "answers": [ "功を奏する", "こうをそうする" ], "comment": "Rank #271 (190 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be tripped up\nto be too drunk to stand\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足を取られる", "あしをとられる" ], "comment": "Rank #272 (187 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to wag one's tail\nto flatter; to butter up\n\nHint: 尻尾を・・・", "answers": [ "尻尾を振る", "しっぽをふる" ], "comment": "Rank #273 (186 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be on track; to be going to plan\nto enter orbit\n\nHint: 軌道に・・・", "answers": [ "軌道に乗る", "きどうにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #274 (186 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be bothered (by something); to suffer\n\nHint: 苦に・・・", "answers": [ "苦になる", "くになる" ], "comment": "Rank #275 (185 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to keep an eye on; to keep a watchful eye on\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を配る", "めをくばる" ], "comment": "Rank #276 (183 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take the initiative; to forestall; to beat to the punch\n\nHint: 先を・・・", "answers": [ "先を越す", "せんをこす", "さきをこす" ], "comment": "Rank #277 (183 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to interrupt (a story, etc.)\nto bend at the waist\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を折る", "こしをおる" ], "comment": "Rank #278 (183 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stop (plug) one's ears\n\nHint: 耳を・・・", "answers": [ "耳を塞ぐ", "みみをふさぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #280 (182 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not know what to do with; to be at a loss with; to have difficulty with; to be put out\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を焼く", "てをやく" ], "comment": "Rank #281 (181 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to join hands\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を結ぶ", "てをむすぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #282 (178 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to remain in memory (of sounds and words); to linger in one's ears\n\nHint: 耳に・・・", "answers": [ "耳に残る", "みみにのこる" ], "comment": "Rank #283 (178 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "as you see\n\nHint: 見ての・・・", "answers": [ "見ての通り", "みてのとおり" ], "comment": "Rank #284 (177 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to settle down (and deal with something); to concentrate all one's energy (on something)\nto settle oneself (in a place); to settle down (somewhere); to settle in\nto take a solid stance; to lower one's center of gravity (centre)\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を据える", "こしをすえる" ], "comment": "Rank #285 (176 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold back others from achieving success; to stand in the way of; to sabotage\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足を引っ張る", "あしをひっぱる" ], "comment": "Rank #286 (174 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "dazzlingly beautiful; brilliant\n\nHint: 目も・・・", "answers": [ "目もあや", "めもあや" ], "comment": "Rank #287 (174 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be captivated by ...; to be fascinated with ...\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を奪われる", "こころをうばわれる" ], "comment": "Rank #288 (171 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to exceed; to be even more (so); to exaggerate\n\nHint: 輪を・・・", "answers": [ "輪をかける", "わをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #289 (171 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel depressed; to be down\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が滅入る", "きがめいる" ], "comment": "Rank #290 (170 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "generous; soft-hearted; having a good personality\n\nHint: 人が・・・", "answers": [ "人が好い", "ひとがいい" ], "comment": "Rank #291 (168 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pass away; to breathe one's last\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を引き取る", "いきをひきとる" ], "comment": "Rank #292 (167 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be unable to stand; to be weak in the knees; to be paralyzed (e.g. with fear) (paralysed); to be dumbfounded\n\nHint: 腰が・・・", "answers": [ "腰が抜ける", "こしがぬける" ], "comment": "Rank #293 (167 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "None of your business!; Don't bother me!\n\nHint: 大き・・・", "answers": [ "大きなお世話", "おおきなおせわ" ], "comment": "Rank #294 (165 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cross over a pass; to finish the most difficult part; to be over the worst (e.g. an illness)\n\nHint: 峠を・・・", "answers": [ "峠を越す", "とうげをこす" ], "comment": "Rank #295 (165 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "incompetent; have no merit\n\nHint: 能が・・・", "answers": [ "能がない", "のうがない" ], "comment": "Rank #296 (164 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get (e.g. the gist of something); to understand\nto turn out as one thought\n\nHint: 意を・・・", "answers": [ "意を得る", "いをえる" ], "comment": "Rank #297 (164 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a distinction; to differ; to be different\n\nHint: 異に・・・", "answers": [ "異にする", "ことにする" ], "comment": "Rank #298 (163 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look towards\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を遣る", "めをやる" ], "comment": "Rank #299 (163 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to burst into flames\nto fire (of a gun)\nto fan a fire with one's breath\n\nHint: 火を・・・", "answers": [ "火を吹く", "ひをふく" ], "comment": "Rank #300 (163 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "as alike as two melons (two peas in a pod)\n\nHint: 瓜二・・・", "answers": [ "瓜二つ", "うりふたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #301 (162 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to raise an objection; to voice an opinion different from those of others\n\nHint: 異を・・・", "answers": [ "異を唱える", "いをとなえる" ], "comment": "Rank #302 (161 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a picture; to be perfect for a picture\npicture-perfect; picturesque\n\nHint: 絵に・・・", "answers": [ "絵になる", "えになる" ], "comment": "Rank #303 (161 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to trust; to relax one's guard (around)\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を許す", "こころをゆるす" ], "comment": "Rank #304 (161 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in short; in a nutshell; in a word; to cut a long story short\n\nHint: 早い・・・", "answers": [ "早い話が", "はやいはなしが" ], "comment": "Rank #305 (161 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take notice (of); to pay attention (to)\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を止める", "めをとめる" ], "comment": "Rank #306 (160 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have no way of knowing; to be completely ignorant of\n\nHint: 知る由も・・・", "answers": [ "知る由もない", "しるよしもない" ], "comment": "Rank #307 (160 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to master (e.g. a skill); to become accustomed to (e.g. a lifestyle); to acquire (e.g. a habit)\nto retain\n\nHint: 身に・・・", "answers": [ "身に付く", "みにつく" ], "comment": "Rank #308 (160 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put on (of clothing); to put (arms) through sleeves\n\nHint: 袖を・・・", "answers": [ "袖を通す", "そでをとおす" ], "comment": "Rank #309 (159 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have a limit; to go too far (e.g. joke)\n\nHint: 程が・・・", "answers": [ "程がある", "ほどがある" ], "comment": "Rank #310 (158 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be beyond one's capacities; to be beyond one's powers; to be beyond one's control; to be unmanageable\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に余る", "てにあまる" ], "comment": "Rank #311 (157 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "small mercy (from some misfortune); silver lining of a dark cloud; consolation in sadness; blessing in disguise\n\nHint: 不幸中の・・・", "answers": [ "不幸中の幸い", "ふこうちゅうのさいわい" ], "comment": "Rank #312 (157 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fall into (someone's) hands; to fall under someone's control; to become someone's property (e.g. of an object)\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に落ちる", "てにおちる" ], "comment": "Rank #313 (157 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be sensible; to be smart; to be tasteful\nto be thoughtful; to be tactful; to be sensitive\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が利く", "きがきく" ], "comment": "Rank #314 (157 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to (keep in) mind; to give heed to; to pay attention to\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気に留める", "きにとめる" ], "comment": "Rank #315 (156 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to speak (of something)\nto be effective; to be powerful; to mean everything\n\nHint: 物を・・・", "answers": [ "物を言う", "ものをいう" ], "comment": "Rank #316 (156 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to attract attention\n\nHint: 注意を・・・", "answers": [ "注意を引く", "ちゅういをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #317 (156 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become fraught with emotion\n\nHint: 胸が・・・", "answers": [ "胸が熱くなる", "むねがあつくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #318 (155 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to think about; to send one's heart out to; to give more than a passing thought to; to think of something far away; to think nostalgically upon (esp. one's hometown)\n\nHint: 思いを・・・", "answers": [ "思いを馳せる", "おもいをはせる" ], "comment": "Rank #319 (155 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cause trouble; to cause a disturbance\n\nHint: 事を・・・", "answers": [ "事を起こす", "ことをおこす" ], "comment": "Rank #320 (155 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose one's temper; to be exasperated; to become irritated\n\nHint: 業を・・・", "answers": [ "業を煮やす", "ごうをにやす" ], "comment": "Rank #321 (154 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unable to move; held up; swamped; stuck between a rock and a hard place\n\nHint: 動きが・・・", "answers": [ "動きが取れない", "うごきがとれない" ], "comment": "Rank #322 (154 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold one's breath; to bate one's breath\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を潜める", "いきをひそめる" ], "comment": "Rank #323 (153 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give up; to admit defeat; to throw in the towel\n\nHint: 音を・・・", "answers": [ "音をあげる", "ねをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #324 (151 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to smile broadly; to grin widely\n\nHint: 相好を・・・", "answers": [ "相好を崩す", "そうごうをくずす" ], "comment": "Rank #325 (151 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "no big deal; no match; not worth worrying about\n\nHint: 目じ・・・", "answers": [ "目じゃない", "めじゃない" ], "comment": "Rank #326 (150 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to side with (someone); to support (someone)\n\nHint: 肩を・・・", "answers": [ "肩を持つ", "かたをもつ" ], "comment": "Rank #327 (148 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "losing everything; coming to nothing; having lost the interest and the principal\n\nHint: 元も・・・", "answers": [ "元も子もない", "もともこもない" ], "comment": "Rank #328 (147 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take off one's hat to a person; to acknowledge another's superiority\n\nHint: 一目・・・", "answers": [ "一目置く", "いちもくおく" ], "comment": "Rank #329 (146 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cool down one's anger\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭を冷やす", "あたまをひやす" ], "comment": "Rank #330 (146 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be to the point; to be pertinent\n\nHint: 的を・・・", "answers": [ "的を射る", "まとをいる" ], "comment": "Rank #331 (146 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "a chill runs down one's spine\n\nHint: 背筋が・・・", "answers": [ "背筋が寒くなる", "せすじがさむくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #332 (145 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be blind to one's shortcomings; to play innocent\n\nHint: 棚に・・・", "answers": [ "棚に上げる", "たなにあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #333 (145 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to let one's guard down\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を許す", "きをゆるす" ], "comment": "Rank #334 (145 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "by all means; by all costs\n\nHint: 何が・・・", "answers": [ "何が何でも", "なにがなんでも" ], "comment": "Rank #335 (144 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be overcome with emotion\n\nHint: 感極・・・", "answers": [ "感極まる", "かんきわまる" ], "comment": "Rank #336 (144 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to kill; to choke the life out of\n\nHint: 息の・・・", "answers": [ "息の根を止める", "いきのねをとめる" ], "comment": "Rank #337 (142 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to try all possible means\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を尽くす", "てをつくす" ], "comment": "Rank #338 (142 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fire oneself up; to give it one's all; to get psyched; to motivate oneself\nto fire someone up (with scolding, corporal punishment, etc.); to rouse\n\nHint: 気合を・・・", "answers": [ "気合を入れる", "きあいをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #339 (141 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to harmonize with; to keep in tune with\nto go along with; to keep in step\n\nHint: 調子を・・・", "answers": [ "調子を合わせる", "ちょうしをあわせる" ], "comment": "Rank #340 (140 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to improve one's skill (esp. at calligraphy or drinking larger amounts of alcohol)\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が上がる", "てがあがる" ], "comment": "Rank #341 (140 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "ill omened (as in \\\"Don't say such an ill omened thing!\\\"); unlucky\n\nHint: 縁起で・・・", "answers": [ "縁起でもない", "えんぎでもない" ], "comment": "Rank #342 (140 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to settle down\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を落ち着ける", "こしをおちつける" ], "comment": "Rank #343 (140 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pick a fight\n\nHint: 喧嘩を・・・", "answers": [ "喧嘩を売る", "けんかをうる" ], "comment": "Rank #344 (139 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to understand from experience\n\nHint: 肌で・・・", "answers": [ "肌で感じる", "はだでかんじる" ], "comment": "Rank #345 (139 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do something for someone in order to create an obligation of gratitude from that person\n\nHint: 恩を・・・", "answers": [ "恩を売る", "おんをうる" ], "comment": "Rank #346 (139 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to incur someone's enmity\n\nHint: 恨みを・・・", "answers": [ "恨みを買う", "うらみをかう" ], "comment": "Rank #347 (138 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to start the debate; to get the ball rolling; to fire the first shot (fig. only); to start a conversation\n\nHint: 口火を・・・", "answers": [ "口火を切る", "くちびをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #348 (138 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to follow in order; to go through step-by-step\n\nHint: 順を・・・", "answers": [ "順を追う", "じゅんをおう" ], "comment": "Rank #349 (138 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to catch one's attention\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に留まる", "めにとまる" ], "comment": "Rank #350 (137 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn inside out; to turn the other way; to turn (something) over\nto look at it from another perspective\nto visit the same prostitute or geisha for a second time\n\nHint: 裏を・・・", "answers": [ "裏を返す", "うらをかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #351 (137 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold a grudge; to hold something against somebody\n\nHint: 根に・・・", "answers": [ "根に持つ", "ねにもつ" ], "comment": "Rank #352 (134 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to worry\n\nHint: 苦に・・・", "answers": [ "苦にする", "くにする" ], "comment": "Rank #353 (134 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to backfire; to produce a result opposite to what was expected or intended\n\nHint: 裏目に・・・", "answers": [ "裏目に出る", "うらめにでる" ], "comment": "Rank #354 (133 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to the core; to the bone; to the marrow\n\nHint: 骨の・・・", "answers": [ "骨の髄まで", "ほねのずいまで" ], "comment": "Rank #355 (133 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get (a joke or explanation); to strike home; to know intuitively\n\nHint: ぴんと・・・", "answers": [ "ぴんと来る", "ぴんとくる" ], "comment": "Rank #356 (133 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "feel uneasy; on tenterhooks; in suspense\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が気でない", "きがきでない" ], "comment": "Rank #357 (132 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to avert one's eyes; to avoid looking straight at something; to cover one's eyes\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を覆う", "めをおおう" ], "comment": "Rank #358 (132 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to behave modestly\n\nHint: 下手に・・・", "answers": [ "下手に出る", "したてにでる" ], "comment": "Rank #359 (132 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be fooled by something; to be taken in\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に乗る", "てにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #360 (132 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "taking a stab at arousing someone's interest\n(of a shrine maiden) presenting water to spirits while invoking them\noffering water before a grave\n\nHint: 水を・・・", "answers": [ "水を向ける", "みずをむける" ], "comment": "Rank #361 (132 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "that's not what you said (before); that's not what was promised\n\nHint: 話が・・・", "answers": [ "話が違う", "はなしがちがう" ], "comment": "Rank #362 (131 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to forgive and forget; to let bygones be bygones; to sweep under the carpet; to wipe the slate clean\n\nHint: 水に・・・", "answers": [ "水に流す", "みずにながす" ], "comment": "Rank #363 (131 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "natural (ability)\n\nHint: 持っ・・・", "answers": [ "持って生まれた", "もってうまれた" ], "comment": "Rank #364 (130 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "being dealt a bad hand (in mahjong, card games, etc.)\npoor (handwriting)\nunscrupulous\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が悪い", "てがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #365 (130 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be grieved at heart; to be troubled; to be worried; to trouble oneself (about something)\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を痛める", "こころをいためる" ], "comment": "Rank #366 (129 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to exert oneself; to devote oneself to\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を入れる", "みをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #367 (129 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel oneself indebted to\n\nHint: 恩に・・・", "answers": [ "恩に着る", "おんにきる" ], "comment": "Rank #368 (129 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to confuse someone; to befuddle someone; to create a smokescreen\n\nHint: 煙に・・・", "answers": [ "煙に巻く", "けむにまく" ], "comment": "Rank #369 (128 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to read too much into things; to get wrong ideas by letting one's imagination run wild; to have a groundless suspicion\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を回す", "きをまわす" ], "comment": "Rank #370 (127 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(I) won't (say) anything no matter what (expression is followed by negative verb relating to say, answer, etc.) to not (tell) even under any threat\n\nHint: 口が・・・", "answers": [ "口が裂けても", "くちがさけても" ], "comment": "Rank #371 (126 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "wearing not a stitch\n\nHint: 一糸まと・・・", "answers": [ "一糸まとわず", "いっしまとわず" ], "comment": "Rank #372 (126 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have readied a bow and stand at ready; to watch for an opportunity; to bide one's time; to wait until the time is ripe\n\nHint: 満を・・・", "answers": [ "満を持す", "まんをじす" ], "comment": "Rank #373 (125 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to devote oneself wholeheartedly to; to sacrifice one's health for; to risk one's life\n\nHint: 体を・・・", "answers": [ "体を張る", "からだをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #374 (125 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to laugh (someone) down\n\nHint: 一笑に・・・", "answers": [ "一笑に付す", "いっしょうにふす" ], "comment": "Rank #375 (125 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give one's life; to lay down one's life\n\nHint: 命を・・・", "answers": [ "命を捨てる", "いのちをすてる" ], "comment": "Rank #376 (122 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to puzzle over; to think deeply about; to rack one's brains over (wrack)\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭をひねる", "あたまをひねる" ], "comment": "Rank #377 (122 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to harm one's health\n\nHint: 体を・・・", "answers": [ "体をこわす", "からだをこわす" ], "comment": "Rank #378 (121 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be delirious with fever; to have a feverish dream\nto be crazy about something\n\nHint: 熱に・・・", "answers": [ "熱に浮かされる", "ねつにうかされる" ], "comment": "Rank #379 (120 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bend one's back; to bow; to stoop\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を屈める", "こしをかがめる" ], "comment": "Rank #380 (120 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to draw a bow; to oppose; to defy; to disobey one's superiors\n\nHint: 弓を・・・", "answers": [ "弓を引く", "ゆみをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #381 (120 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make fun of; to look down on; to make light of\nto take a tea break; to rest\n\nHint: 茶に・・・", "answers": [ "茶にする", "ちゃにする" ], "comment": "Rank #382 (120 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be pretentious; to put on airs\n\nHint: 見栄を・・・", "answers": [ "見栄を張る", "みえをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #383 (120 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to finish off; to ensure (something) is dead; to deliver the coup de grace\nto put an end to; to deliver the final blow\nto be the best for A\n\nHint: 止めを・・・", "answers": [ "止めを刺す", "とどめをさす" ], "comment": "Rank #384 (119 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to learn; to acquire knowledge\nto carry; to wear (clothes, etc.); to put on\n\nHint: 身に・・・", "answers": [ "身に付ける", "みにつける" ], "comment": "Rank #385 (118 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "cannot do a thing; feeling handcuffed; being at the end of one's tether; being at one's wit's end\n\nHint: 手も・・・", "answers": [ "手も足も出ない", "てもあしもでない" ], "comment": "Rank #386 (118 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have a lot on one's shoulders; to bear a lot of responsibility\n\nHint: 荷が・・・", "answers": [ "荷が重い", "にがおもい" ], "comment": "Rank #387 (117 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to speak unanimously; to speak in chorus; to speak in unison; to speak in one voice\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を揃える", "くちをそろえる" ], "comment": "Rank #388 (117 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be scared\n\nHint: 恐れを・・・", "answers": [ "恐れをなす", "おそれをなす" ], "comment": "Rank #389 (117 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give a warning; to remind (a person) of\n\nHint: 釘を・・・", "answers": [ "釘をさす", "くぎをさす" ], "comment": "Rank #390 (117 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "rightly or wrongly; by all possible means\n\nHint: 是が・・・", "answers": [ "是が非でも", "ぜがひでも" ], "comment": "Rank #391 (116 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sit cross-legged\nto rest on one's laurels\n\nHint: 胡坐を・・・", "answers": [ "胡坐をかく", "あぐらをかく" ], "comment": "Rank #392 (116 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become independent\nto leave one's hands; to leave one's possession\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を離れる", "てをはなれる" ], "comment": "Rank #393 (116 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be dizzy; to feel faint; to feel giddy\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が回る", "めがまわる" ], "comment": "Rank #394 (115 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unthinkable; count for nothing; not matter; out of the question\n\nHint: 問題に・・・", "answers": [ "問題にならない", "もんだいにならない" ], "comment": "Rank #395 (115 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to spread one's roots (of a tree, etc.); to take root (of an ideology, etc.)\n\nHint: 根を・・・", "answers": [ "根を張る", "ねをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #396 (115 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be consistent; to be coherent\n\nHint: 辻褄が・・・", "answers": [ "辻褄が合う", "つじつまがあう" ], "comment": "Rank #397 (114 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make one's best effort; to be enthused; to put your back into it\n\nHint: 身が・・・", "answers": [ "身が入る", "みがはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #398 (113 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to attack the enemy in his unguarded moment\n\nHint: 虚を・・・", "answers": [ "虚を衝く", "きょをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #399 (113 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be struck with terror; to be terrified; to be scared to death\n\nHint: 肝を・・・", "answers": [ "肝を冷やす", "きもをひやす" ], "comment": "Rank #400 (112 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be palatable; to suit one's taste\n\nHint: 口に・・・", "answers": [ "口に合う", "くちにあう" ], "comment": "Rank #401 (112 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "awkward; uncomfortable; embarrassing\n\nHint: ばつが・・・", "answers": [ "ばつが悪い", "ばつがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #402 (112 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sink deeply into one's mind; to come home to; to go to one's heart\nto pierce one's body (e.g. of wind, cold, etc.)\n\nHint: 身に・・・", "answers": [ "身に沁みる", "みにしみる" ], "comment": "Rank #403 (111 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do in earnest; to concentrate on; to apply one's mind to\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を入れる", "きをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #404 (111 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to resolve; to make up one's mind; to decide\n\nHint: 腹を・・・", "answers": [ "腹を決める", "はらをきめる" ], "comment": "Rank #405 (111 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to dirty one's hands\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を汚す", "てをよごす" ], "comment": "Rank #406 (111 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to keep in mind; to memorize\n\nHint: 頭に・・・", "answers": [ "頭に入れる", "あたまにいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #407 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be sacked; to be fired; to be dismissed\nto be beheaded\n\nHint: 首に・・・", "answers": [ "首になる", "くびになる" ], "comment": "Rank #408 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become a habit\n\nHint: 癖に・・・", "answers": [ "癖になる", "くせになる" ], "comment": "Rank #409 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unable to take one's eyes off of something; having to keep a watchful eye on\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が離せない", "めがはなせない" ], "comment": "Rank #410 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take (adopt) measures\n\nHint: 策を・・・", "answers": [ "策を講ずる", "さくをこうずる" ], "comment": "Rank #411 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose one's presence of mind; be flummoxed; to get flustered\n\nHint: 度を・・・", "answers": [ "度を失う", "どをうしなう" ], "comment": "Rank #412 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to originate with; to start with; to stem from\n\nHint: 端を・・・", "answers": [ "端を発する", "たんをはっする" ], "comment": "Rank #413 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be pleased; to gloat; to glow with self-satisfaction\n\nHint: 悦に・・・", "answers": [ "悦に入る", "えつにいる" ], "comment": "Rank #414 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to faint; to swoon; to lose consciousness\nto be astounded; to astonished\nto have a busy time; to be hectic\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を回す", "めをまわす" ], "comment": "Rank #415 (109 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stay in one's heart; to be enduringly memorable; to be unforgettable\n\nHint: 心に・・・", "answers": [ "心に残る", "こころにのこる" ], "comment": "Rank #416 (109 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to worry; to fret; to get anxious\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を揉む", "きをもむ" ], "comment": "Rank #417 (109 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be adrift in the streets; to be out in the cold\n\nHint: 路頭に・・・", "answers": [ "路頭に迷う", "ろとうにまよう" ], "comment": "Rank #418 (108 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be free; to be available\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が空く", "てがあく" ], "comment": "Rank #419 (107 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to win fame; to be widely-known; to be well known; to make a name for oneself\n\nHint: 名を・・・", "answers": [ "名を馳せる", "なをはせる" ], "comment": "Rank #420 (107 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to meddle; to poke one's nose into; to interfere\nto make a pass at; to flirt with; to make a move on\n\nHint: ちょっかいを・・・", "answers": [ "ちょっかいを出す", "ちょっかいをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #421 (106 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel under pressure; to feel impatient; to be in a hurry\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が急く", "きがせく" ], "comment": "Rank #422 (106 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stay up all night; to sit up all night; to do something all night\n\nHint: 夜を・・・", "answers": [ "夜を徹する", "よをてっする" ], "comment": "Rank #423 (106 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to beat someone to the punch; to get the drop on (someone); to forestall\n\nHint: 機先を・・・", "answers": [ "機先を制する", "きせんをせいする" ], "comment": "Rank #424 (106 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "right on the heels of yesterday, then today ...; soon after something, and yet now ...\n\nHint: 昨日の・・・", "answers": [ "昨日の今日", "きのうのきょう" ], "comment": "Rank #425 (105 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "point blank; blunt\n\nHint: 身も・・・", "answers": [ "身も蓋もない", "みもふたもない" ], "comment": "Rank #426 (105 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bear fruit\n\nHint: 実を・・・", "answers": [ "実を結ぶ", "みをむすぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #427 (105 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be touching; to be moving\n\nHint: 胸を・・・", "answers": [ "胸を打つ", "むねをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #428 (105 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make the smart move (after taking in the situation, etc.)\nto do the tactful or helpful thing (after considering someone's feelings)\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を利かせる", "きをきかせる" ], "comment": "Rank #429 (103 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to assume a posture; to pose; to make a defiant (proud) gesture\n\nHint: 見得を・・・", "answers": [ "見得を切る", "みえをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #430 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be away from home; to be out of the house\n\nHint: 家を・・・", "answers": [ "家を空ける", "いえをあける" ], "comment": "Rank #431 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be widely known; to be famous\n\nHint: 音に・・・", "answers": [ "音に聞く", "おとにきく" ], "comment": "Rank #432 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be away from home; to be out of the house\n\nHint: 家を・・・", "answers": [ "家を空ける", "うちをあける" ], "comment": "Rank #433 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be bloodthirsty\n\nHint: 血に・・・", "answers": [ "血に飢える", "ちにうえる" ], "comment": "Rank #434 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to spare time (for)\n\nHint: 時間を・・・", "answers": [ "時間を割く", "じかんをさく" ], "comment": "Rank #435 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "being painfully-true (e.g. reprimand); making one's ears burn; striking home (e.g. remark)\nhaving an earache; feeling pain in one's ear\n\nHint: 耳が・・・", "answers": [ "耳が痛い", "みみがいたい" ], "comment": "Rank #436 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stand side by side; to stand in a row\n\nHint: 軒を・・・", "answers": [ "軒を連ねる", "のきをつらねる" ], "comment": "Rank #437 (101 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "forming a crowd; ganging up on; joining forces against\n\nHint: 寄っ・・・", "answers": [ "寄ってたかって", "よってたかって" ], "comment": "Rank #438 (101 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to curry favour; to butter up; to fawn over; to humour someone (humor); to put in a good mood (e.g. a baby)\n\nHint: 機嫌を・・・", "answers": [ "機嫌を取る", "きげんをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #439 (101 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go too far; to go to excess; to carry too far\n\nHint: 度が・・・", "answers": [ "度が過ぎる", "どがすぎる" ], "comment": "Rank #440 (101 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a mess of; to sacrifice; to waste\n\nHint: 棒に・・・", "answers": [ "棒に振る", "ぼうにふる" ], "comment": "Rank #441 (101 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose one's cool; to blow one's top; to flip one's lid; to get angry\n\nHint: 頭に・・・", "answers": [ "頭に血がのぼる", "あたまにちがのぼる" ], "comment": "Rank #442 (101 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "There is nothing more that can be done\n\nHint: 万事・・・", "answers": [ "万事休す", "ばんじきゅうす" ], "comment": "Rank #443 (100 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to trip someone up; to pull the carpet from under\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足をすくう", "あしをすくう" ], "comment": "Rank #444 (100 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "just like that; in the twinkling of an eye; in the blink of an eye; in the time it takes to say \"ah!\"\n\nHint: あっと・・・", "answers": [ "あっと言う間に", "あっというまに" ], "comment": "Rank #445 (100 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do something unexpected\n\nHint: 意表を・・・", "answers": [ "意表を突く", "いひょうをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #446 (100 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be struck by lightning\nto be yelled at (by someone of higher status); to be scolded harshly\n\nHint: 雷が・・・", "answers": [ "雷が落ちる", "かみなりがおちる" ], "comment": "Rank #447 (100 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be taken aback; to be dumbfounded\n\nHint: 毒気を・・・", "answers": [ "毒気を抜かれる", "どっけをぬかれる" ], "comment": "Rank #448 (100 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unfounded (e.g. rumour); groundless; baseless; completely untrue\n\nHint: 根も・・・", "answers": [ "根も葉もない", "ねもはもない" ], "comment": "Rank #449 (98 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "embarrassed; awkward\nunlucky; inopportune\n\nHint: 間が・・・", "answers": [ "間が悪い", "まがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #450 (98 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "narrow gate; obstacle; school (position) hard to enter (get)\n\nHint: 狭き・・・", "answers": [ "狭き門", "せまきもん" ], "comment": "Rank #451 (97 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "long-awaited; eagerly awaited\n\nHint: 待ちに・・・", "answers": [ "待ちに待った", "まちにまった" ], "comment": "Rank #452 (97 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be remembered; to go down in history\n\nHint: 名を・・・", "answers": [ "名を残す", "なをのこす" ], "comment": "Rank #453 (97 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unable to compete with; not able to make a dent in (e.g. a problem); not able to get a solid hit in (e.g. in a fight)\nhard to chew\n\nHint: 歯が・・・", "answers": [ "歯が立たない", "はがたたない" ], "comment": "Rank #454 (96 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to encourage to do (something); to urge a person on; to demand action\nto spank; to give a spanking; to hit someone on the bottom; to beat someone's backside\n\nHint: 尻を・・・", "answers": [ "尻を叩く", "しりをたたく" ], "comment": "Rank #455 (96 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "sink or swim; high-stakes; desperate\n\nHint: 一か・・・", "answers": [ "一か八か", "いちかばちか" ], "comment": "Rank #456 (95 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "gushing forth; bursting out\n\nHint: 堰を・・・", "answers": [ "堰を切ったよう", "せきをきったよう" ], "comment": "Rank #457 (95 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a good showing\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を吐く", "きをはく" ], "comment": "Rank #458 (95 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to steel oneself to; to brace oneself\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を張る", "きをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #459 (95 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to envision how things will turn out (usu. unfortunate)\nto have foresight; to be able to see the future\n\nHint: 先が・・・", "answers": [ "先が見える", "さきがみえる" ], "comment": "Rank #460 (94 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to enter a New Year\n\nHint: 年を・・・", "answers": [ "年を越す", "としをこす" ], "comment": "Rank #461 (94 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to rack one's brain\n\nHint: 知恵を・・・", "answers": [ "知恵を絞る", "ちえをしぼる" ], "comment": "Rank #462 (94 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unexpected; unforeseen; inconceivable\n\nHint: 思いも・・・", "answers": [ "思いも寄らない", "おもいもよらない" ], "comment": "Rank #463 (94 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pin a crime on\n\nHint: 罪を・・・", "answers": [ "罪を着せる", "つみをきせる" ], "comment": "Rank #464 (94 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to smile with one's whole face\nto squint\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を細くする", "めをほそくする" ], "comment": "Rank #465 (94 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the more one looks (at it) the more...\n\nHint: 見れ・・・", "answers": [ "見れば見るほど", "みればみるほど" ], "comment": "Rank #466 (93 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be deceived\n\nHint: 一杯・・・", "answers": [ "一杯食う", "いっぱいくう" ], "comment": "Rank #467 (93 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "bolt from the blue; great surprise\n\nHint: 寝耳に・・・", "answers": [ "寝耳に水", "ねみみにみず" ], "comment": "Rank #468 (93 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look stupid; to have a critical lack\n\nHint: 間が・・・", "answers": [ "間が抜ける", "まがぬける" ], "comment": "Rank #469 (93 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel refreshed; to feel more cheerful; to feel better\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が晴れる", "きがはれる" ], "comment": "Rank #470 (92 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pour oil on (something); to anoint with oil\nto turn up; to add fuel (e.g. to a dispute); to rev up; to encourage\n\nHint: 油を・・・", "answers": [ "油を注ぐ", "あぶらをそそぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #471 (92 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bring to naught; to bring to nought; to waste\n\nHint: 無に・・・", "answers": [ "無にする", "むにする" ], "comment": "Rank #472 (91 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the end of the line; the end of the road; curtains\n\nHint: 一巻の・・・", "answers": [ "一巻の終り", "いっかんのおわり" ], "comment": "Rank #473 (91 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "liberated woman\n\nHint: 新し・・・", "answers": [ "新しい女", "あたらしいおんな" ], "comment": "Rank #474 (91 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be dizzy; to be disoriented\nto be dazzled\nto be lost in (greed, lust, etc.)\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が眩む", "めがくらむ" ], "comment": "Rank #475 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have the the end in sight; to see the mountains\n\nHint: 山が・・・", "answers": [ "山が見える", "やまがみえる" ], "comment": "Rank #476 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become stiff; to tense\n\nHint: 堅く・・・", "answers": [ "堅くなる", "かたくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #477 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look on enviously while doing nothing\n\nHint: 指を・・・", "answers": [ "指をくわえる", "ゆびをくわえる" ], "comment": "Rank #478 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get carried away; to push one's luck; to push a good thing too far\n\nHint: 図に・・・", "answers": [ "図に乗る", "ずにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #479 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to speak to; to give a (something) talk to; to speak words of (something)\n\nHint: 言葉を・・・", "answers": [ "言葉を掛ける", "ことばをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #480 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get distracted; to jump off the track\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が散る", "きがちる" ], "comment": "Rank #481 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be attentive to small details\nto be attentive to others (or others' concerns)\nto have one's mind turn groundlessly to something negative\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が回る", "きがまわる" ], "comment": "Rank #482 (89 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "incorrigible; dogged\n\nHint: 性懲りも・・・", "answers": [ "性懲りもない", "しょうこりもない" ], "comment": "Rank #483 (89 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to carry in one's pocket; to own\nto take; to carry about\n\nHint: 懐に・・・", "answers": [ "懐にする", "ふところにする" ], "comment": "Rank #484 (89 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take a solid stance\nto put one's back in it; to exert oneself\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を入れる", "こしをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #485 (89 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "before or since; neither before nor after; no other time in one's life; stressing a particular moment or event as being unique or most extreme\n\nHint: 後に・・・", "answers": [ "後にも先にも", "あとにもさきにも" ], "comment": "Rank #486 (88 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(a person) to admit defeat; to turn tail (and run)\n(a dog) to tuck one's tail between one's legs\n\nHint: 尻尾を・・・", "answers": [ "尻尾を巻く", "しっぽをまく" ], "comment": "Rank #487 (88 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to apply the art of resuscitation (in judo, etc.)\nto breathe life into; to stimulate; to encourage someone; to give someone a pep talk\n\nHint: 活を・・・", "answers": [ "活を入れる", "かつをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #488 (87 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go with the flow; to go with the times\n\nHint: 波に・・・", "answers": [ "波に乗る", "なみにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #489 (87 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make the sign of the cross; to bless oneself; to cross oneself\n\nHint: 十字を・・・", "answers": [ "十字を切る", "じゅうじをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #490 (87 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(carrying) close to one's person; next to the skin\n\nHint: 肌身・・・", "answers": [ "肌身離さず", "はだみはなさず" ], "comment": "Rank #491 (87 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be flurried; to be confused; to lose one's head\n\nHint: 泡を・・・", "answers": [ "泡を食う", "あわをくう" ], "comment": "Rank #492 (87 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "sick; nauseated\nangry; irritated\n\nHint: 胸が・・・", "answers": [ "胸が悪い", "むねがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #493 (86 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to tag along; to follow; to tail; to shadow\nto leave tracks; to leave footprints\n\nHint: 跡を・・・", "answers": [ "跡をつける", "あとをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #494 (86 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to happen to hear; to overhear\n\nHint: 小耳に・・・", "answers": [ "小耳に挟む", "こみみにはさむ" ], "comment": "Rank #495 (86 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become independent\nto leave one's hands; to leave one's possession\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が離れる", "てがはなれる" ], "comment": "Rank #496 (85 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose hope\n\nHint: 目の・・・", "answers": [ "目の前が暗くなる", "めのまえがくらくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #497 (85 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to welter in blood; to be covered in blood\n\nHint: 朱に・・・", "answers": [ "朱に染まる", "あけにそまる" ], "comment": "Rank #498 (84 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be in a tizzy; to be in a frenzy; to have one's eyes light up; to have a different look in one's eyes\n\nHint: 目の・・・", "answers": [ "目の色を変える", "めのいろをかえる" ], "comment": "Rank #499 (84 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "poor hearing\n\nHint: 耳が・・・", "answers": [ "耳が遠い", "みみがとおい" ], "comment": "Rank #500 (84 occurrences in 1300 novels)" }
]
}
